自动字幕整理+翻译：SuperBart  原作者LGR于2021-2-3在LGR Blurbs上发布
Greetings blurbs, got a thing here. Check this thing out.
大家好啊，我给大家说说这个东西
This is the margie... margie... emm I don't know.
这是个Margi牌的便携式VGA输出装置，用的是SD卡接口
Presenter-to-Go SD Card VGA Output thingy.
Yeah, this is, uh, something that y'all let me know about
我上期做惠普iPAQ移动相机视频时
注：BV1Wz4y1S7fY 惠普掌机式移动相机 @ LGR & wu_dl
when I did my video on the HP iPAQ Pocket Camera.
你们就不停地向我安利这个了
Yeah,(I) did a video on that.
没错，我上个视频已经说过了
Digital camera that goes into an SDIO card slot interface
给掌上电脑和PDA设计的
通过SD卡接口连接的数码相机
and Pocket PCs and PDAs.
Yeah, I've got this here that I'm going to try this with because
现在为了体验一下这个，我把iPAQ又拿出来了
I had never heard of this until some of y'all left some comments.
要不是观众老爷在评论区说的话，我还不知道呢
And check it out. It's just a VGA output dongle thing
这个就是一个插在SD卡接口上的
that plugs into the SD card slot, to really, SDIO slot there.
更准确地说，插在SDIO接口上的VGA输出适配器
注：SD插槽只能接存储卡，而SDIO插槽可以接各种设备，诸如GPS设备，相机等
And gives a VGA output of some emm... kind.
然后输出一些VGA信号
But I don't know, I didn't actually see this iPAQ listed
不过我有点没底，我看包装上没有写
as something that it would work with specifically.
这个能100%适配我这个机器
But, that kind of makes sense.
不过，这也能理解
This predates, this particular iPAQ model.
这个比那台iPAQ的发售日期早
Seems like it should though. The requirements aren't...
我觉得应该行，硬件要求也不太具体
I don't know, too particular? It just says you need
盒子上说，只要你的设备在支持列表上就能用
A Pocket PC handheld from the supported list and...
Like I said, it's not on there.
然而我的没在上面
So anyway, let's just go ahead and (voice stuck) and open it up.
无论如何，赶紧开个箱
And this is kind of cool.
有点意思哈
So you got this nice little carrying pouch here.
这有个十分耐人的小包
We'll open that up.
一会再打开
It does smell leathery. It's actually kind of nice.
闻上去是皮革的，挺用心的
It got that new car kind of a degradation smell.
这种老化的味道跟新车的味道一样
It's like certain materials they degrade and they smell like a new car.
就是说，某种材质老化了，然后散发出新车的味道
Anyway, I got a CD-ROM here with the software
然后这里有CD，里面装着软件
so this is just a windows side of things.
所以这跟电脑就有关了
I've already installed this on my Windows XP machine.
我已经将其装在了XP古董机上
And got it transferred over like the the file that it needs onto the Pocket PC.
然后将必要的文件都传送到了iPAQ上
So it's on there, ready to go.
现在万事具备，只欠东风
And we got this right here, which is again, extremely basic.
我还翻到了这个，十分普通的说明书
I think this is pretty much it. You get in English.
估计就这点东西吧，这是英文那页的
It's just like, uh... yeah, plug it in (to) use it.
一句话：插上去开始用
The complete user manual is available on the CD.
完整版说明书在CD上
And yeah, it also has a PowerPoint tutorial on the CD as well
CD上还有PPT版教程
that you can look at to see how to use it.
看完PPT，你就明白怎么用了
Yeah, everything else is just in other languages,
剩下的语言我全部不认识
So this is all you get.
所以我就介绍到此了
And it is pretty fitting that it comes with a
这个东西附带一个PPT展示
tutorial in PowerPoint presentation form.
我觉得还挺好的
Because this really is built for on-the-go PowerPoint presentations.
因为它就是用来很方便地投射PDA上的PPT的
So if you had your PDA, and your PowerPoint on there ready to go back in the day,
如果你那时有PDA，并且里面还有PPT的话
then there you go, and it's got this margie...8-(
接上后要用这个叫Maggie.....（迷惑读音
Anyway, you got this mirror application.
反正用这个投影程序就行了
So, let's get this unpacked and run that.
所以说，我们来拿出那个神秘的设备吧
And... Yeah, like I said, sort of built for PowerPoint presentations,
我刚说过，这个是用来演示PPT
some slide show type of stuff.
或是某种幻灯片啥的
And that kind of has me thinking that
这让我想到了
maybe it won't be exactly VGA output that's very live.
也许它的VGA信号输出不是实时的
I don't know. Like I said, I haven't really tested it yet.
然而我还没试，所以我也说不好
I've just... I have turned it on, that's about it.
我刚才只是将机器启动了一下
So you've got the little dongle in here...
现在给大家展示的就是适配器了
and you got VGA out on that side.
这边是VGA输出接口
And then the little SDIO interface part right there.
这个是要插入SDIO接口的
And then, of course, that just goes in... like that.
至于怎么插进去，不用多说了吧
And it's got the same issue where it's just going to slide right out,
而这个和那个摄像头一样，容易滑出来
with no problem, because SD card slots were meant to
也好理解，因为SD卡槽本身设计是
have things inserted in there and
将东西完全插进里面的
they don't really hold on to things that are in there.
而像这种有外置的东西就接不住了
So anyway, that's the thing.
所以说，你只好小心点了
So you got to be careful with it.
And it's got a VGA cable here, just a little short one.
本身还附带了一条VGA线缆，挺短的
I don't know, foot long or something.
也就一英尺长吧
There's a... a remote? I guess that's what the little things are for on the sides
还有个遥控器，估计转接盒侧面的小玩意
like IR sensors. Check that out.
就是个红外线传感器吧
Again, made for PowerPoint presentations.
毕竟是用来放PPT的
You know, moving slides forward and backward.
也就是向前向后翻一页
And I'm assuming they interface with certain programs or... something.
我觉得这个应该有个配套程序吧
And... it does require external power.
而且，这个转接器还要用外置电源
So you have this little thing right here, that is...
就是这个大家喜闻乐见的玩意啦
Yeah, those 5V 600mA, 0.1A input.
5V*600mA=3W, 输入电流0.1A
So that plugs into the back of the dongle,
这个要插入转接器的后面
and get this back out of here.
而那个就要要插进插座了
So it's really not the most elegant solution,
所以我说这个没那么优雅
but it does the trick if you need VGA output on the PDA.
但如果你需要将PDA里的东西用VGA输出的话
There you get (it) go.
你只能用这个了
I mean, this is pretty cool.
这个确实很酷
Like the whole idea of having VGA output of ANY KIND...
只要将PDA里的东西用VGA输出的话，就挺先进的
on a PDA is just fantastic.
You know, much less.
就用这些东西（不是
Through the SD card slider, SDIO.
插进SD接口，通过SDIO输出
This is so cool.
听上去就挺高大上
Uh, anyway, let's test it out!
现在赶紧测试吧
Okay, I got a CRT here. VGA cable just going to plug that in...
好的，CRT显示器已经准备好了，VGA接口正准备接入
to a little box. And I got power going to that.
转接器也接好电了
And then the PDA, just plug it in.
现在我把其接入PDA
And it immediately switches over to the output of the box
立马转接器的信号就输出了
which is just a blank screen by default.
默认是个白屏，啥也没有
So if we open up the Margie application: Margie Mirror.
现在我将投影软件Margie Mirror打开
We can see that we've got some options there
这里有些选项
in terms of enabling it, zooming it, updating and rotating.
包括开启，放大，刷新频率和旋转屏幕
So let's just enable.
现在咱启动吧
(Chuckle) Look at that! Oh man.
快看看，快看看啊╰(*°▽°*)╯
That is a fantastically sharp image.
图像锐利得简直是不得了
See that is zoomed. There's that.
现在我把放大功能给关了
So that's as zoomed in as they can go,
这就是放大功能了，确实挺好
but still, that is awesome.
Let's see what we're dealing with here.
看看目前的输出情况吧
Sixty hertz, oh yeah, that's right.
60Hz，确实是这样
(However), this one doesn't show the the resolution.
然而它没有显示分辨率
Well it is 60 hertz, so let's change the updated speed. I'm not sure...
目前是60Hz刷新率，现在我把刷新频率调高些，然后就
Yeah it's still going to do this.
好吧，一点都没变
You know, obviously it's not in real time.
显然，这个不是实时刷新的
I think what it's doing is taking a screen shot.
我觉得转接器得先截个图
And then, like buffering it in here, maybe transferring it to the
然后缓冲到屏幕上，也许先将其传送至
SD card... storage? Maybe? I don't really know if there's storage, but...
SD卡上的存储设备......这上面真有存储设备吗？
Obviously it takes a little bit to render out on the screen.
反正渲染显示得花点时间啦:-|
I do like that you can rotate as well. That's pretty handy.
这个能转向，挺好用的功能
At least it could be.
我觉得吧
But yeah, it's effectively just showing a static... image.
这个只能显示静态图像了
And that's it. So it's not really a complete, uh, like screen sharing type of thing.
并不是完全的屏幕共享
Now I guess this is a game that I was... playing previously.
我觉得这个游戏我之前玩过
Interesting... It is actually updating faster
有点意思啊，玩纸牌的时候
注：一般咱说的Windows附带纸牌都叫克朗代克
when it's on solitaire, isn't it?
这玩意更新快了些
It's yeah, okay. That's quicker, but...
没错，是快了点，但是
[Laughter] obviously still not real time.
很明显这个不是实时更新的
This is fascinating, man. I don't really know what it's doing exactly.
这确实挺好的，但我还是不太明白其背后的原理
It does seem to be that, the more stuff is on screen to refresh, the slower it is.
我发现，屏幕上的东西越多，屏幕刷新得越缓慢
So maybe it is trying to figure out what it sees
也许转接器先判断前后
as being different and then, only updating that part of the screen.
显示的不同，然后只更新那一块屏幕
I don't know, but this is neat.
要真是这样的话，确实挺精巧的
[Chuckle]Even if it's not a direct video feed.
尽管它输出的不是视频流
I don't know, man. I don't know how it's exactly doing it.
说真的我真不知道其背后的原理
Anyway, that's pretty much what this is.
无论如何，该展示的我都展示了
It's kind of awesome at the same time,
但确实很不错。虽然它刷新得确实很慢
though, it's just, yeah, very very slow.
But nothing else. It provides an easy way to very quickly get screen shots
但瑕不掩瑜。它确实能很快地提供PDA实时的画面
instead of having to, you know, use something within the Pocket PC itself to take a screen shot.
总比用PDA截完图再投射好多了吧
Like I can have this directly connected to... a capture device over there.
我现在直接可以将转接器接到采集设备
In fact, let me go ahead and do that right now. I'll just switch over...
既然说到这了，我现在给大家展示一下效果
To some capture device footage.
现在我把信号切到了转接器
Yeah. I mean, you can capture directly from a PDA like this.
没错，你可以像这样直接从PDA采集信号
It's just very slow, so it's not going to be good for capturing any kind of game-play.
然而还是很慢，所以这个并不适合采集游戏实况
But, you can see how this would be fantastic for presentations on the go.
不过，能很方便地展示PDA显示还是挺好的
PowerPoint things and any kind of, you know, even photos, slide shows.
诸如PPT之类的，甚至是图片秀，幻灯片
That's just... I can see this being highly appealing to business users.
我觉得这个对商业用户来说十分合适
And yeah, even folks that just want to bore people with their vacation pictures.
或者是那些喜欢显摆自己度假照片的小布尔乔亚:-P
Why not? Especially if you have a little camera add-on too.
你要是有了相机附件的话，为何不再来个这个呢？
Oh, before we go and one last thing here, got the remote.
最后，我给大家说一下遥控器
I wanted to try this out and see... maybe how this worked.
我一开始是想看看这个是怎么用的
I believe it's just for switching through slides and PowerPoint whatnot.
我觉得这个跟翻页笔一样，能翻页
But uh, unfortunately, check that out.
不过，可惜的是，里面的电池给腐蚀了
You got a corroded little battery in there.
Yeah, don't see those corrode, terribly often, but it did.
虽然这样的腐蚀并不太常见，但这个确实是这样
This is a... CR2025, I don't have one of these, another one.
这个是 CR2025 电池，我手里没有
注： CR2025是一类纽扣电池 电压3V 容量150mAh 重量2.5g
So I'm not able to test this right now.
所以现在我测试不了
I don't have PowerPoint on there anyway.
我PDA上面也没装PowerPoint
So I don't even know if it would do anything.
所以我不知道播放PPT时的效果
Well uh, that's it, LGR blurbs. Thanks for watching.
无论如何，我讲完了。感谢大家收看
SuperBart：祝大家新春快乐:-)